Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're
talking a little bit about Small Talk.
That's right, we are getting
towards the end of our series.
Actually this is
the last podcast
that we will have all about
Small Talk and we're just going
to be following Mr. Campbell
and Michelle and Melissa.
And they're just going
to talk very briefly about
the weather, about
traveling, very casual things.
That's right, so let's take
a listen to this dialogue
and we'll be back in a moment
to discuss what's going on.
Hi ladies, thanks for picking me up.
It's awful weather out there.
Absolutely, it's been raining for hours.
How are you, Melissa? Are you okay?
I'm great thanks, Mr. Campbell. Do you have
any business trips plans in, Mr. Campbell?
Of course, I'm always
traveling. I'll leave for London
next Monday and then
I'll fly to Boston from there.
It's going to be a busy month.
How about you, Michelle?
Do you have any vacation plans?
Yes, Mike and I will travel to
Beijing to see my experience for
the Spring Festival and hopefully
next year we will visit London.
I hear it's a wonderful city. I couldn't
agree more. London is really fantastic.
It's my favorite city. I'm
sure you'll have a great time.
All right, we're back, so now let's
take a look at language takeaway.
All right, we don't have that
much today in language takeaway.
We do have a couple of really
important words and phrases.
The first one comes
from the very first line,
Mr. Campbell says, "Hi ladies,
thanks for picking me up." That's right.
Now there's a phrasal verb to pick
someone up means to get them, right?
To gather them, to collect
them. You can do this with a car.
I will pick you
up at the airport.
You can also do it in person
by just walking to a place
and meeting somebody and
then taking them somewhere else.
That's the important part.
You take them somewhere else.
So maybe if you go pick
your kids up from school, you
just walk there, you get
them, and you walk back home.
That's right. And so the key
here is that you remember that the
verb goes, "First, I will pick,"
and then you have the person.
I will pick you up. I will pick them up.
He will pick us up.
That's right.
So the subject goes between pick and up.
That's right. All right.
So we're going to pick someone up.
And then Mr. Campbell
comments on the weather.
He says, "It's awful
weather out there.
" It's awful. All right. So
awful. You listen to the tone.
You automatically think that
this is probably a bad thing.
And you're right. It's a bad thing.
But what's another way to say awful?
It's terrible. It's bad. It's horrible.
So awful is a way to say
something's really bad.
And we use it very often with the weather.
This weather is awful.
But we can also use it about
other things, like food, for example.
So if you have something
to eat, and it doesn't taste
good, you can say, "This
is awful. What is this?
" Or, "What's that awful smell?"
Oh, Marco took his shoes off.
Right. An awful smell. All right.
And, well, Mr. Campbell went on to tell
them that he's taking another trip soon.
But a specific kind of trip.
All right. So you know that there
are many different kinds of trips.
But the one that he's
taking is a business trip.
So normally we could just say,
"I'm going on a trip next year.
" But here, we specify.
We say, "It's a business trip.
" So what are we doing
on this trip, Marco?
That's right. So we're basically working.
We're going because our company needs us to
go to a meeting or to do some work abroad.
All right. So you know on
a business trip that you'll
be doing work things,
you'll be having meetings.
You will not be going to Disney World.
You will not be meeting with
friends and going to movies, probably.
Right. Exactly.
So it's very different from a vacation.
A vacation you go with the
objective of going to these fun places.
So can I say, "I'm going
on a business vacation?
" No. You're either going on
vacation, or you're taking a business trip.
All right. Business trip.
So now let's take a break
and let's review our dialogue.
Hi, ladies. Thanks for picking me up.
It's awful weather out there.
Absolutely. It's been raining for hours.
How are you, Melissa? Are you okay?
I'm great. Thanks, Mr. Campbell.
Do you have any business trips
planned soon, Mr. Campbell?
Of course, I'm always
traveling. I'll leave for London
next Monday, and then
I'll fly to Boston from there.
It's going to be a busy month.
How about you, Michelle?
Do you have any vacation plans?
Yes. Mike and I will travel to Beijing to
see my experience for the spring festival.
And hopefully next year we will visit
London. I hear it's a wonderful city.
I couldn't agree more.
London is really fantastic.
It's my favorite city. I'm
sure you'll have a great time.
All right, so now let's take a look at
four key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right, now we have a great phrase
for everybody here in fluency builder.
Melissa is talking to Mr. Campbell,
and he asks her how she is. Are you okay?
And she says, I'm great.
Thanks. Now, Marco, why would
we use this phrase instead
of, I'm fine. Thank you.
Well, it's basically
the same thing.
It's just another way of
answering this common question.
How are you? You can
say I'm fine. Thank you.
I'm well, but this is just
another way of saying, I'm okay.
All right, but I think it's
important too to remember that
this is also very casual like
the rest of the conversation.
And a pretty enthusiastic. She's great. So
it's important to remember that I'm fine.
Thanks is standard. It's
very normal, but I'm great.
It's a nice way to change it
and do something different.
That's right. Okay. And now
we wanted to ask if we have any
plans, but we wanted to know
if we have any vacation plans.
And the interesting thing
about this question was that Mr.
Campbell said
any vacation plans.
So that's how he's,
that's the whole sentence.
Well, first he says, how about
you, Michelle? Any vacation plans?
So what we think here is that
maybe it's wrong. Do you have any
vacation plans is something
that we, we'd want to hear, right?
But here we don't actually
need to say, do you have any
vacation plans because it's
pretty clear who we're talking to.
We're talking to
Michelle, right? Right.
And we're talking about traveling
and we're talking about plans.
So it's overstated that we don't
really need to say, do you have
any vacation plans? We're
already talking about the subject.
Now this is a great way to transition. One
person is talking about himself or herself.
And then you want to talk about the
other person. So you say, what about you?
Mm-hmm. Any vacation plans
or any dinner plans or any ideas?
Exactly. So it's a, it's a
great way to, like you say,
transition from one idea or
from one person to another.
Mm-hmm. Now to the next phrase,
a very common one, specifically
when you are not really sure about
something, but somebody told you.
Specifically in this case,
Michelle says, I hear
it's a wonderful city when
talking about London.
So what does she mean
by, I hear it's a wonderful city.
Well, basically, Michelle is saying she's
never been to London, but she's read
or she's heard from friends or from a
TV show that London's a wonderful city.
So she can't say, it is a wonderful
city because she's never been there.
But she can say, listen,
you know, I have, I have
heard this from other
people or from magazines.
So it's, it's not even clear where she
heard it, but that's not really important.
So basically the idea is that we
don't know personally, but we have
friends that told us or we have
read in an magazine or a TV show.
We've seen it that it's great. So you can
use it with many things like a restaurant.
That's right. I hear the food
is delicious. Or I could say,
hey, Marco, I'm going to
Hong Kong Disneyland next year.
Right. And I can say, oh, I
hear that it's a very fun place.
So Marco, you've never been there, right?
No, I've never been there. Okay.
All right. And to finish
off Mr. Campbell agrees
completely about London
being such a wonderful city.
And he says, I couldn't agree more.
I couldn't agree more.
So he agrees. We understand that.
But I couldn't agree more is
like saying, I really, really agree.
Right. Like you are completely right.
Yeah. So this is a way to exaggerate.
You know, you want to say, I agree.
It's a little boring.
So you say, I couldn't agree more.
I'm agreeing the most I can.
That's right. And then we
can also use the opposite,
which would be if you
disagree with someone.
I couldn't disagree more. So
you just changed that one word.
I couldn't disagree more.
So maybe I don't like London.
Maybe it's too rainy or too dark for me.
So I say, I couldn't disagree more.
I think London is terrible.
Maybe not the right
thing to say in a small talk
situation, but we can
talk about that in a minute.
Exactly. All right.
So let's review everything one last time.
Hi, ladies. Thanks for picking me up.
It's awful weather out there.
Absolutely. It's been raining for hours.
How are you, Melissa? Are you okay?
I'm great. Thanks, Mr. Campbell.
Do you have any business trips
planned soon, Mr. Campbell?
Of course. I'm always
traveling. I'll leave for London
next Monday and then
I'll fly to Boston from there.
It's going to be a busy month.
How about you, Michelle?
Do you have any vacation plans?
Yes. Mike and I will travel to Beijing to
see my experience for the spring festival.
And hopefully next year we will visit
London. I hear it's a wonderful city.
I couldn't agree more. London is
really fantastic. It's my favorite city.
I'm sure you'll have a great time.
All right. So this is our last
podcast, all about small talk.
And well, I hope it's been useful.
We've gotten some great feedback
about the different topics and small
conversations you can have with
a stranger, a co-worker, a friend.
To kind of not have that awkward silence.
That's right. We've gone
over a lot of different situations.
We've had situations with strangers,
situations with work, friends. But I think
what's really important is that in
all these situations, we're very polite.
We say nice things.
There are these transitions
like I hear or I
couldn't agree more.
These are wonderful ways of really
being nice to the person you're talking to.
That's right. And we're going to
come out with a new series soon.
So we would really like
your feedback, any topics
or any specific subject
you want us to talk.
You can let us
know at EnglishPod.
com and also your questions
and comments can be left there.
That's right. So please
get in touch with
us. EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.